Robert S. McNamara Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Subject File, 1946-2006 (Box II:36-77)
  - Vietnam War Project: “Missed Opportunities?” See also Container II:80, Argument without End
    - Correspondence (Box II: 77)
      - General, 1993-1998
    - Graham, Thomas W., “report card,” 1997
    - Notes, 1995-1997
    - Press clippings, 1994-1997
    - Symposium, “After the Cold War: Reassessing Vietnam,” Center for the Study of the Vietnam Conflict, Texas Tech University, Lubbock, Tex., 1995
    - Transcripts, 1998
- Part II: Speeches and Writings, 1934-2006 (Box II:78-128)
  Correspondence, drafts and typescripts, notes, background and research material, transcripts, agreements and contracts, proposals and outlines, proofs, biographical material, publication and production material, copyright releases and permissions, blurbs and endorsements, reviews, royalty statements, printed matter, and miscellaneous material concerning McNamara's articles, books, commentary, editorials, interviews, radio and television appearances, and speeches as well as speeches and writings by others.
  - Articles and miscellaneous writings (Box II:78)
    - About McNamara
      - Hendrickson, Paul, “A Man Divided against Himself,” Washington Post, 1988
      - Index to reference material about McNamara, compiled by Gordon Jones, 1996
      - Morris, Thomas, “Robert S. McNamara: Pentagon Genius,” published in Giants in Management (1985), edited by Robert L. Haught, 1978
      - Printed copies and typescripts, 1961-1969, 1985-2005, (2 folders) (Box II: 79)
    - By McNamara
      - Correspondence and drafts, 1997-2005
      - Editorials, 1992-1993, 1999-2005
      - Printed copies, 1982-2001, (2 folders)
      - Titles
        - “The Conference on Disarmament Should Focus on Steps To Move Toward a “Nuclear Free World',” Disarmament Diplomacy, 1996
        - Foreword for War No More by Robert Hinde and Joseph Rotblat, 2003
        - “Nuclear Weapons and Global Security,” with Hans Bethe and Kurt Gottfried, 1990-1991
  - Biographical material (Box II: 80)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-1981, 1987-1997
    - Who's Who entries, 1972-2000
  - Blurbs and endorsements, 1990, 1997, 2004
  - Books
    - Argument without End See also Container II:73, Vietnam War Project
      - Blight, James G., and Janet M. Lang
        - Correspondence, 1997-2000, (4 folders)
        - Miscellany, 1997-1999
      - Book tour, 1998-1999, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1997-2001 (Box II: 81)
      - Cushman, John H., 1970, 1993-1997
      - Drafts
        - Rough drafts and notes, 1997-1998
        - Working copies, 1998
          - Bellagio draft
            - McNamara corrected text
            - Text, front matter and chapters 1-7, (3 folders)
          - Biersteker, Thomas J., chapter 8 (Box II: 82)
          - Blight, James G., chapter 7, (2 folders)
          - Brigham, Robert K., chapter 7
          - McNamara, Robert
            - Front matter, chapters 1-4, (2 folders)
            - Chapters 5-6, (2 folders) (Box II: 83)
          - Miscellaneous
          - Schandler, Herbert Y., chapter 7, (2 folders)
        - Editing by Geoffrey Shandler, 1998 (Box II: 84)
          - First edit
          - Chapter edits with McNamara's revisions
            - Front matter, chapters 1-6, (2 folders)
            - Chapters 7-8, appendices (Box II: 85)
          - Revised edit
      - Editing comments, 1998
      - Miscellany, 1985, 1997-1999
      - “Missed Opportunities?” transcripts from Hanoi Conferences, Vietnam War Project, 1998
      - Notes, 1998
      - Proposals and outlines (Box II: 86)
        - Meetings
          - 1997, Aug. 6, Thomas J. Watson, Jr. Institute for International Studies, Brown University, Providence, R.I.
          - 1998
            - Jan. 6, Washington, D.C., 1997-1998
            - Feb. 7-8, Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C.
              - Agenda and background material, (2 folders)
              - General
            - Mar. 28-30, Thomas J. Watson, Jr. Institute for International Studies, Brown University, Providence, R.I.
              - General
              - Welch, David (Box II: 87)
            - July 27-31, Bellagio Conference, Bellagio, Italy, 1997-1998
            - Aug. 30, Thomas J. Watson, Jr. Institute for International Studies, Brown University, Providence, R.I.
        - Osnos, Peter, meetings, 1997-1998
      - Reviews, 1999-2000
      - Royalties, 1999-2005
      - Schandler, Herbert Y., 1977, 1984, 1996-1999
      - Vassar College, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., meeting, 1999
      - Why Did We Fight the War?” television program, Japan Broadcasting Corp. (NHK), 1964-1969, 1998 (Box II: 88)
      - Writings by McNamara, 1999
    - Blundering into Disaster, book reviews, 1986-1987
    - In Retrospect
      - Abstract, 1995
      - Agreements and contracts
        - In Retrospect, 1993-1997
        - “In Retrospect II,” (published as Argument without End ), 1998-1999
      - American Gold Star Mothers, 1995
      - Articles
        - About McNamara
          - Alter, Jonathan, “Confessing the Sins of Vietnam,” Newsweek, interview transcript and printed copy, 1995 See also Container II:89, “We Were Wrong, Terribly Wrong”
          - Miscellaneous, 1996-1999
        - By McNamara (Box II: 89)
          - Letter to the editor, New York Times, in response to “McNamara's War, and Mine,” by Louis G. Sarris, 1995
          - “We Were Wrong, Terribly Wrong,” Newsweek, 1995 See also Container II:88, Alter, Jonathan
      - Audio book, 1995
      - Background and research material
        - Chapter 2, “The Early Years,” 1961-1967, 1992
        - Chapter 3, “The Fatal Fall of 1963,” 1963-1972, 1992-1994
        - Chapter 4, “A Time of Transition,” 1963-1964
        - Chapter 5, “The Tonkin Gulf Resolution,” 1964, 1970, 1984-1994 (Box II: 90)
        - Chapter 6, “The 1964 Election and Its Aftermath,” 1964-1965, 1993, (2 folders)
        - Chapter 7, “The Decision to Escalate,” 1965 (Box II: 91)
          - Jan.-June, (2 folders)
          - July (Box II: 92)
        - Chapter 8, “The Christmas Bombing Pause,” 1965-1966 See also Classified, (2 folders)
        - Chapter 9, “Troubles Deepen,” 1965-1967, (2 folders) (Box II: 93)
        - Chapter 10, “Estrangement and Departure”
          - Chronological file
            - 1967, May-Sept.
            - 1967, Oct.-1968, 1993 (Box II: 94)
          - Comments on strategy memorandum, 1967
          - Departure from Defense Department, 1967-1968, 1984
          - March on the Pentagon, 1967, 1984
          - “Pennsylvania” channel, 1967, 1979-1983, 1994
          - Senate Committee on Armed Services, Preparedness Investigating Subcommittee (Stennis hearings), 1967
        - Chapter 11, “The Lessons of Vietnam,” 1968-1994 (Box II: 95)
        - Miscellaneous, 1961-1971, 1978-1994 See also Oversize
      - Comments and criticisms (pre-publication reviews)
        - Aubrac, Raymond, 1993-1994
        - Bundy, McGeorge
          - Correspondence, 1993-1995
          - Editing comments on draft, 1993-1994
            - Chapters 1-5
            - Chapters 6-10 (Box II: 96)
          - Interview of McNamara (with Brian VanDeMark), transcript, 1994
          - Speeches and lectures, 1971, 1993-1994
        - Bundy, William P., 1993-1995
        - Eiseman, Ben, 1993-1994
        - Goldberg, Alfred, 1993-1994
        - Karnow, Stanley, 1994
        - Letters to commentators, 1993-1994
        - Miscellaneous, C-W, 1993-1994 (Box II: 97)
        - Pastor, Robert A., 1993-1994
        - Richardson, Elliot L., 1994
        - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1993-1994
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1993-1995
        - Personal, B-V, 1993-1995
        - Public reaction and response, 1995-2001
          - A-C, (2 folders)
          - D-Z, (6 folders) (Box II: 98)
      - Declassification and security reviews (Box II: 99)
        - Correspondence and access requests, 1993-1998, (3 folders)
        - Documents
          - Declassified, 1961-1970, (2 folders)
          - Declassified subsequent to book publication, 1963-1969, (2 folders) (Box II: 100)
      - Drafts and notes
        - First draft, notes and outlines, 1993-1994
          - Front matter and chapters 1-8, (3 folders)
          - Chapters 9-11, appendices (Box II: 101)
        - Miscellaneous, 1994
        - Photographic layout, 1994-1995
        - Revised drafts
          - Full text, 1994
            - Chapters 1-6
            - Chapters 7-11 (Box II: 102)
          - Partial text, 1994
      - Editing and planning
        - Correspondence, 1994
        - Meetings, transcripts
          - 1993-1994, July, (3 folders)
          - 1994, Sept. (Box II: 103)
        - Notes, 1993-1994
      - Expenses, 1993-1995
      - Foreign editions, 1995-1996
      - Gibbons, William Conrad, The U.S. Government and the Vietnam War: Executive and Legislative Roles and Relationships, part 4, 1994, (2 folders)
      - Goulding, Philip G., 1993-1995 (Box II: 104)
      - Graham, Katharine, book party, 1995
      - Interviews conducted by McNamara and Brian VanDeMark, transcripts
        - Ginsburg, David, 1994
        - Goldberg, Alfred, and others, 1994
        - Hamburg, David, 1994
        - May, Ernest, and Richard Neustadt, 1994
        - Osnos, Peter, 1994
        - Warnke, Paul, 1994
        - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1993
      - Miscellany, 1989-1995 (Box II: 105)
      - Osnos, Peter, 1994-1995
      - Paperback edition
        - Editing and revisions, 1995-1996
        - Halberstam, David, “Dead Wrong,” Los Angeles Times Book Review, 1995-1996
      - Permission requests, 1993
      - Press clippings, 1993-2000, (3 folders)
      - Proposal and outlines, 1993
      - Publicity and tours
        - Advertisements and best seller lists, 1995
        - Interviews (Box II: 106)
          - Background material and notes, 1968, 1992-1996
          - Personal appearances and schedules, 1995-1996
        - Speeches and lectures
          - “In Retrospect,” drafts, 1995-1996
          - Miscellany, 1995
        - Welsh, Anne Morrison, 1995-1998
      - Reviews, 1995-1998
      - Rostow, W. W., 1995
      - Royalties
        - Donation of profits, 1995
        - Statements, 1995-2005 (Box II: 107)
      - Sterling Lord Literistic, Inc., 1993-1995
      - University of California, Berkeley, Calif., background material for meetings, 1994-1996
      - VanDeMark, Brian
        - Correspondence, 1991-1995
        - Draft papers
          - “Robert S. McNamara and His Times,” 1993
          - “A Way of Thinking,” 1993
        - Interviews of McNamara, transcripts, 1993-1994, (2 folders)
        - Seminar, U.S. Naval Institute, 1996
    - Out of the Cold, 1989-1990 (Box II: 108)
    - Wilson's Ghost
      - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, manuscript critique meeting, Cambridge, Mass., 2000
        - Notes
        - Transcripts
      - Background and research material
        - Background books
          - Chapter 2, “Preventing Great Power Conflict,” 1957, 1992-2000
          - Chapter 3, “Reducing Communal Killing,” 1956-1958, 1977, 1993-2000
          - Chapter 4, “Avoiding Nuclear Catastrophe,” 1983-1999 (Box II: 109)
        - Global security, 1999
        - Kosovo, 1995-1999
        - Miscellaneous, 1983-1991, 1999-2001
        - “The Role of the U.S. in the World in the Twenty-First Century,” 1996-2000
      - Blight, James G., and Janet M. Lang
        - Correspondence
          - 1999
          - 2000-2001, (2 folders) (Box II: 110)
        - Miscellany, 2001-2002
      - Blurbs and jacket copy, 2001
      - Book tour
        - Correspondence and schedules, 2001
        - Miscellany, 2001
        - Presentation and script, 2001, (1 folder) (Box II: 111)
      - Contract, 2001
      - Correspondence, 2000-2002
      - Drafts
        - First draft, 2000
        - Second draft, 2000
        - Third draft, 2000
          - Front matter, chapters1-2, (2 folders)
          - Chapters 3-5, (2 folders) (Box II: 112)
        - Fourth draft, 2001
        - Miscellaneous, 1999-2000
      - Footnotes, circa 2000
      - Miscellany, 1999
      - Notes, 1999-2000
      - Paperback edition
        - Drafts, preface and afterword, 2003, (2 folders)
        - General, 1998-2003
      - Proposals and outlines, 1999-2000 (Box II: 113)
      - Reviews, 2001-2002
      - Royalties, 2001-2005
      - Writings by McNamara, 2000-2001
  - Copyright releases and permissions, 1984-2004, (4 folders)
  - Documentary films
    - Correspondence, 1996-2006, (2 folders)
    - Deadly Mistakes, 2004
    - The Fog of War (Box II: 114)
      - Background and research material
        - Ford Motor Co., 1954-1962, 1993
        - Great Depression, 1934-1937, 1996
        - “Interview reference material number 3,” 1965-1968, 1993-2001
        - Japanese bombing of Shanghai, China, 1937, 1986
        - Miscellaneous, 2002
        - Presidential tapes, transcripts, 1963-1965
        - Secretary of defense
          - Issues and crises, 1962-1963, 1971, 1989-2001
          - Notes and miscellaneous documents, 1963-1968, 1994, 2001 See also Classified
        - World War II
          - Miscellaneous documents, 1944-1945, 1976, 1986-2002
          - Wheeler, Keith, Bombers over Tokyo, 1982 (Box II: 115)
      - Blight, James G., and Janet M. Lang
        - Correspondence, 2002-2004, (3 folders)
        - Miscellany, 2001-2002
        - “’Telling the Truth' in The Fog of War ,” 2003
      - Corrections, 2002
      - Correspondence, 2002-2004
      - DVD edition, 2003-2004
      - Miscellany, 2003-2004 (Box II: 116)
      - Morris, Errol
        - Correspondence, 2001-2004
        - Interview transcripts, 2001-2002, (3 folders)
      - Notes, 2001-2002
      - Photographs, 2003
      - Press schedules, 2003
      - Reviews and commentary, 2003-2004, (2 folders)
      - Scout Productions, First Person, television program (Box II: 117)
        - Correspondence and notes, 2000-2002
        - Interview transcript, 2001
      - Screenings and interviews
        - Cannes Film Festival, Cannes, France, 2003
        - Miscellaneous, 2003-2004
        - Telluride Film Festival, Telluride, Colo., 2003
      - Transcripts, 2002-2003
    - Losing Control, 1988-1991
  - General, 1978-1981, 1997-2006
  - Interviews
    - Correspondence, 1997-2006
    - Listing of audiotapes, 1972-1991
    - Office of the Secretary of Defense Historical Office, oral history interviews, 1993-2001, (2 folders) (Box II: 118)
    - Printed copies, transcripts, and typescripts, 1968, 1983-2005, (3 folders)
    - Requests
      - 1973-1975, 1982-1983, 1993-1998
      - 1999-2005 (Box II: 119)
  - Public statements, printed and typescript copies
    - 1979-1998, (6 folders)
    - 1999-2006, (5 folders) (Box II: 120)
  - Radio and television appearances
    - British Broadcasting Corp., 1995-1999, 2005
    - Cold War, CNN television series, 1997-1998 (Box II: 121)
    - Correspondence, 1990-2005, (2 folders)
    - History Channel, 1997-2001
    - Japan Broadcasting Corp. (NHK), 1997-2005
    - Primetime Live, ABC television, 1995
  - Speeches, lectures, and symposia
    - Chronological file
      - 1990, Nov. 7, “A Vision of the Post-Cold War World,” lecture in Legacy of Strategic Bombing series, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1967, 1990
      - 1993
        - Jan. 14, “A Vision for Our Nation in the Twenty-First Century,” (“Restructing America”)
          - Background and research material
            - Press clippings, 1991-1993
            - Printed matter and typescripts, 1992-1993
          - Correspondence, 1992
          - Drafts and notes, 1992-1993
        - Apr. 15, “A Global Population Policy to Advance Human Development in the Twenty-First Century,” Planned Parenthood of Hawaii, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1992-1993 (Box II: 122)
      - 1995
        - June 22, “A Vision of Global Security in the Twenty-First Century,” Peace Research Institute, Frankfurt, Germany
        - Sept. 1, “A Vision of U.S. Security in the Twenty-First Century,” International Peace University, Berlin, Germany, 1994-1995
      - 1996
        - Feb. 15, “A Vision of Global Security in the Twenty-First Century,” Brown University, Providence, R.I.
        - Apr. 11-18, Regents' Lectures, University of California, Berkeley, Calif.
          - General, 1995-1996
          - Lectures, 1996
            - Miscellaneous
            - “The State of Our Nation at the End of the Twentieth Century”
              - Background and research material
              - Drafts
              - Notes
        - June 28, “A Vision of Global Security in the Twenty-First Century,” Sao Paulo, Brazil
          - Background and research material, 1995-1996
          - General, 1996
          - Leigh Bureau, 1995-1996 (Box II: 123)
          - Typescripts, 1996
        - Nov. 7, “A Vision of Global Security in the Twenty-First Century,” Denver Medical Library, Denver, Colo.
      - 1997, Apr. 9, “A Vision of Global Security, and the Role of Nuclear Weapons in the Twenty-First,” Japan Atomic Industrial Forum, Tokyo, Japan
      - 1998, Feb. 11, “Reflections on War in the Twentieth Century”
      - 2005, Mar. 3, “The Folly of U.S. and NATO Nuclear Weapon's Policies,” John Ben Shepperd Public Leadership Institute, University of Texas of the Permian Basin, Odessa, Tex.
    - Correspondence, 1988-2006, (2 folders)
    - Drafts and typescripts
      - 1986, 1992-1993
      - 1994-2004, v; (6 folders) (Box II: 124)
    - Miscellany, 1988-1994, 2004-2005 (Box II: 125)
    - Notes, 1994-1998
    - Printed copies, 1966, 1995
  - Writings by others
    - Articles and miscellaneous writings
      - Brown, Christopher
        - Background and research material, 1946-1947, 1993-1997
        - Correspondence, 1993-2004 See also Classified, (2 folders)
      - Gilpatric, Roswell L., “A Civilian Reflections on the Defense Establishment,” undated
      - Mathews, Jessica T., “Africa: Continent in Crisis,” 1988
      - Printed copies and typescripts, 1983, 1993-1996, 2001-2002, (2 folders) (Box II: 126)
      - Thomas, Evan, 1997-2000
    - Books
      - Hendrickson, Paul, The Living and the Dead, 1996
      - Ignatius, Paul R., On Board, drafts and page proofs, 2005
      - Shapley, Deborah, Promise and Power
        - Correspondence
          - Miscellaneous, 1993
          - Shapley, Deborah, 1992-1994
        - Interviews
          - Index and summaries, 1994
          - Transcripts
            - 1984
            - 1985-1988, (4 folders) (Box II: 127)
            - 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box II: 128)
        - Miscellany, 1993
        - Reviews, 1992-1994
    - Interview, transcript of Roswell L. Gilpatric interview by Dennis O'Brien, 1970
    - Speeches
      - Introductions of and tributes to McNamara, 1986-1989, 1995-1998
      - Typescripts, 1985, 2001-2004
- Part II: Miscellany, 1960-2009 (Box II:128-136)
  Correspondence, appointment books, financial and legal papers, photographs, greeting cards, press clippings, real estate records, notes, reports, land plans and surveys, social clubs and engagements, recreational and travel records, printed matter, and other items, including condolence letters and memorial tributes on the death of McNamara's wife, Margaret.
  - Addresses, 1980, undated (Box II:128)
  - Appointment books, 1997-1999
  - Birthdays and Christmas holidays
    - Cards and greetings, 1984-1999
    - Lists, 1982-1986 (Box II: 129)
  - Correspondence
    - Crank letters, 1988-1996
    - Fan mail, 1998-2000, (2 folders)
    - General
      - Blight, James G., and Janet M. Lang, 1988, 1996-2005
      - Clinton, Bill and Hillary, 1992-1997
      - Cohen, William S., 1996-1997
      - Halberstam, David, 1996
      - Jordan, Vernon, 1994-1999
      - Kissinger, Henry, 1996-2000
      - May, Ernest R., 1994-1997
      - McKinnon, Michael, 1996
      - Strickland, Phil, 1996-1997
      - Strong, Maurice, 1991-1998
      - VanDeMark, Brian, 1991-2000
  - Death of McNamara, memorial message, 2009 (Box II: 130)
  - Donations and endowment funds
    - Miscellaneous, 1960, 1993-1997
    - Robert S. and Margaret C. McNamara Foundation, 1981-1985, 1997-1999
  - Financial records
    - AmeriVest, 2000
    - Caspian
      - Accounts and financial statements, 1995-1997
      - Board of Directors meetings
        - 1996, (4 folders)
        - 1997, (5 folders) (Box II: 131)
      - Correspondence, 1995-1998
      - General, 1995-1997
      - Information memoranda, 1996-1997, (3 folders) (Box II: 132)
      - Telephone conference calls, 1996-1997
    - Miscellaneous, 1977, 1987, 1996
  - John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, 1995-1997
  - Lists of gift books and photographs, undated
  - McNamara, Margaret Craig
    - Death of
      - Condolences, 1981
        - Index
        - Telegrams
      - Memorial service, transcription, 1981
    - Interviews concerning Margaret Craig McNamara
      - Miscellaneous, undated
      - Travis-Robyns, Suzan, 1995-1997, 2004
    - Margaret McNamara Memorial Fund, 1983-2002 (Box II: 133)
    - Memorial mountain huts See also Container II:134, Tenth Mountain Trail Association
      - Correspondence, 1980-1996
      - Press clippings, 1981-1988
    - Photographs, 1961-1966
    - Tributes, 1993
  - Notes, 1994, 2000
  - Passports and visas, 1961-1996
  - Photographs, 1994
  - Press clippings, 1990-1994, (2 folders)
  - Real estate
    - Martha's Vineyard, Mass., 1986-2000
    - Snowmass, Aspen, Colo.
      - Aspen Valley Improvement Association
        - Miscellany, 1981-1982, 1988-1991
        - Surveys
          - Aspen Institute, 1988
          - Pitkin County Airport, 1987-1988 (Box II: 134)
      - Correspondence, 1983-1999
      - Snowmass Homeowners Association, 1984-1990, 1999
      - Tenth Mountain Trail Association, 1982-1996 See also Container II:133, Memorial mountain huts, (2 folders)
      - Woodrun II
        - Correspondence, 1985-1998
        - Legal records, 1966-1975, 1987
    - Washington, D.C., 1999
  - Recreation and travel
    - Africa, 1999
    - China, 2003
    - Italy, 1994-1995 (Box II: 135)
    - Jordan, 1993-1995
    - Miscellaneous, 1985, 1996
    - Norway, 1997-2001
    - Pakistan, 1991-1992
    - Ski trips, 1990-1997
  - Social and recreational clubs
    - Cosmos Club, Washington, D.C., 1969-2001, (3 folders)
    - Economic Dinner Group, Ann Arbor, Mich., 1983-1988
    - Edgartown Yacht Club, Edgartown, Mass., 1992-2004
    - Federal City Club, Washington, D.C., 1997-1998
    - Metropolitan Club, Washington, D.C., 1988-2001
    - Pacific-Union Club, San Francisco, Calif., 1981, 1987, 1994-2001 (Box II: 136)
    - River Club of New York, New York, N.Y., 1996-1998
    - St. Albans Tennis Club, Washington, D.C., 1981-1986, 1992-1998
  - Social engagements
    - General, 1967-1982, 2004-2005
    - Invitations, 1996-2001
  - Telephone messages and notes, 1969, 1995-1998, 2005
- Part II: Classified, 1962-2002 (Box II:CL 1)
  Correspondence, memoranda, telegrams, background and research material, position papers, notes, reports and studies, and related items.
  - Organizations (Box II:CL 1)
    - Eminent Persons Group on Curbing Illicit Trafficking in Small Arms and Light Weapons
      - General, 2000 (Container II:16)
  - Subject File
    - Cuban Missile Crisis
      - Originals and copies of primary documents
        - Miscellany, 1962-1963 (Container II:46) See also Sensitive Compartmented Information
    - Defense department
      - Memoranda, position papers, and reports, 1968 (Container II:65)
      - Nuclear Posture Review, 2002 (Container II:65) See Formerly Restricted Data
      - Reports and studies
        - Achievements and issues, 1968, undated (Container II:65)
  - Speeches and Writings
    - Books
      - In Retrospect
        - Background and research material
          - Chapter 8, “The Christmas Bombing Pause,” 1966 (Container II:92) See Top Secret
    - Documentary films
      - The Fog of War
        - Background and research material